Enrico Lucia

IRELAND

Tel (IE): +353 (0)834430386 Email: enrico.lucia.web@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Develop efficient and intuitive user interfaces via Front end best practices for web applications while continuing to learn and expand my knowledge of emerging web technologies.

PROFILE

A self-motivated professional with experience dominant experience in front end web development, plus marketing and design on high traffic websites including ryanair.com (largest low cost airline in Europe), altroconsumo.it, prelet.co.uk, bidbid.co.uk, safari-dating.com, knowledgetoaction.co.uk and cadogan.com

DEMONSTRATED STRENGTHS INCLUDE:

- Working independently, efficiently and accurately within a large team of developers, designers, product managers and project managers utilizing Perforce to manage code, Jira to manage bug tracking and Rally to assist in the Agile software development methodology as well as Waterfall environment.
- Strong knowledge of web 2.0 best practices for Front End scripting, SEO, UX, Social Networking, Split A/B Interface Testing, Content Sharing, Asynchronous BackEnd/Frontend, RSS and JSON/JSONP.
- The ability to plan strategically and work through highly iterative design and UX journey phases while meeting strict deadlines within Agile Scrum Team methods.
- Proven ability to continually learn and grow within the field of web development, design and marketing. Most of my skills nowadays are self taught with the help of mentors, online resources and challenging projects within a professional environment.

EXPERIENCE

Lead Front-End Web Developer – Ryanair Airline – JUL 2013– Current Ryanair.com / Dublin, Ireland

Ryanair is Europe's favourite low fares airline, operating more than 1,600 daily flights (over 500,000 per year) from 68 bases, across 1,600 low fare routes, connecting 186 destinations in 30 countries and operating a fleet of 300 new Boeing 737-800 aircraft. Ryanair has recently announced firm orders for a further 175 new Boeing aircraft, which will be delivered between 2014 and 2018. Ryanair currently has a team of more than 9,000 highly skilled professionals, will carry over 81.5 million passengers this year and has an outstanding 29-year safety record.

- Currently the core Front End Developer working on new version of ryanair.com.
- Wrote main core functionalities on front end that receive 15 million views per day.
- Developed front end implementation and usability of public REST APIs in Javascript / Backbone.js / Underscore.js / Require.js to get millions of queries per day.
- Developed front end implementation for real-time flight seach engine (skyscanner.com look alike) to get best fares on different filters.

- Developed Javascript modules; e.g. analytics plugin used to track user behavior, bookings, etc.
- Front End compatibilities debugging for tablets e.g. iOS tablets and Android tablets to ensure the most achevable user experience throughout the website.
- Developed and tested Ryanair corporate/investors website using Bootstrap best practices.
- ✗ Developed and tested Ryanair responsive newsletters in 14 different languages.
- Conducting and examining candidates interviews for Design and Development vacancy roles.
- * Training and assisting new members of our Team in both Front End and Design.
- * Mentoring all med/jr Front End developers throughout daily and long terms tasks.
- Main web technologies used while in this position include javascript, Backbone.js, Angular.js, jQuery, Grunt, Yeoman, Bower, Handlbars, Less, Sass, Require.js, Bootstrap, iOS and Android debugging tools, JSPX, Tomcat, XML, RSS, Mercurial

Senior Front-End Web Designer / Developer - VizionOnline Itd. - OCT 2011 – JUN 2013 viziononline.co.uk / London, UK

VizionOnline is a professional website design service London UK working with a number of leading brands.

As the most experienced member of the team I had a heavy influence on the running of the department. As such, I used my existing knowledge and experience to increase the efficiency of the team and improve the quality of their work.

Furthermore, as part of my commitment to learning I began to study User Experience Design which lead to me introducing a range of user-centred design techniques into the development process. This new focus on the experience of the end-users transformed the agency's output from quite standard websites for local businesses to high-traffic websites and ecommerce solutions.

- **×** Build and maintain from psd to the final for the final result for new and existing websites to support new web 2.1 standards.
- * As lead of a internation teamwork, I manage in maintaining/adding features requiring AJAX, DOM manipulation and API interaction. This includes website features such as a mobile optimisation, cross-browsable testing with multiple devices, SEO, user-friendly front end, eye-catching layout.
- Designed and developed Prelet.co.uk one of the most known and used website for Landlord furntiures impleted by using OpenCart and hand-written modules to support high-flow remote management with pre-compiled xls files.
- Design and develop sites and email marketing assets for each client.

- Create a modify existing modules for Wordpress, OpenCart and Joomla to client's specs according to the newest standards available at the moment achieved in most of the cases with PHP and Jquery.
- * Helped launch a more outstanding corporate website for VizionOnline.
- * My foremost contribution to the front-end team is to work client-side ideas and prespective management of the final produc to provide a practical pixel perfect UI based on the design team's specs. This is achieved mostly with HTML/CSS in a PHP framework. A strong understanding of javascript/jQuery and basic understanding of PHP is required to achieve success with this. In most of the cases I created UI mockups in Photoshop and provide them to the clients to help find a practical design solution that supports quality visual design, feature extensibility and code efficiency.
- * My workflow includes managing my own team projects using Adobe Suite, IIS and Apache. For development workflow I use Dreamweaver/Coda, JSLint, firebug (firebug lite for IE), chrome devtools, jsfiddle, jQuery, jQueryUI, YSlow and W3C and CSS Validator.
- * Main web technologies used while in this position include javascript, Backbone.js, Angular.js, jQuery, Grunt, PHP, HTML/CSS, JSPX, XML, RSS and Mercurial
- Main platforms used while in this position include OpenCart, Magento, Wordpress, OsCommerce

Senior Front-End Web Designer / Developer - Teknoassist - FEB 2010 - OCT 2011 teknoassist.it/ Rome, IT

Teknoassist is a leading company providing web services particularly focused on lawyers. Lead for the Teknoassist corporate website and supervised a team of developers to assure consistency throughout all online channels.

Consulted on-site with clients for design and development of information kiosks. Developed training materials to be used by publishing experts in the development of italian law online materials. Assisted in the creation of company Web Standards and the mentoring of new employees. Developed Style Guides to streamline communications with cross-functional teams. Designed and deployed PHP/Javascript applications for divisional intranets to be used as educational tools.

- * Assist in the planning process for all site marketing initiatives
- ✗ Design and develop site and email marketing assets
- * Maintain the company's brand and strategy through all web channels
- * Provide creative and content support for social networking and affiliate programs
- * Migrated content to new platform for a major site-redesign
- * Retrofitted all existing HTML/CSS to validate
- Create and mantain a well-structured data-entry platform for a national well-known law consultancy company in Italy
- ✗ Implemented SEO on all static web content
- Won company award "Sito web dell'anno 2011 Categoria: Confronto" ('Website of the Year 2011 Category: Compare') www.altroconsumo.it, entirely developed and designed by my teamwork using.Reference can be found here: http://www.sitowebdellanno.it/pastwinners.php

- Create and implement a hand-written Corporate CMS
- Most work was accomplished using Adobe CS5,Coda,Dreamweaver,firebug,W3C and CSS Validator
- Conducting competitor analyses on rival websites to identify the strengths and weaknesses of alternative solutions or new approaches
- Main web technologies used while in this position include javascript, AJAX, JSON, jQuery, PHP, HTML/CSS
- * Main platforms used while in this position include OpenCart, Wordpress

Web Designer / Developer, Marketing Coordinator - Puntonet - MAY 2009 - NOV 2009 puntonet.biz/ Rome, IT

As Web Designer / Developer I have worked alongside a team of Project Managers, Editors/Producers and creative sales strategists on a day-to-day basis. As Web Designer / Develope responsible for ensuring that mock-ups, pitches and final products were delivered to often challenging deadlines, and that marketing actions were executed on budget and on time to the complete satisfaction of client and agency partners.

- Migrated content to new platform for a major site-redesign
- Managed email marketing program
- Maintain the company's brand and strategy through all web channels
- Designed/developed creative for affiliate and email marketing programs
- * Provided IT support
- * Reworked organisational workflow to dramatically increase quality control
- * Retrofitted all existing HTML/CSS to validate
- Create and implement a hand-written Flash CMS
- Designed/developed creative for affiliate and email marketing programs
- Worked directly with customers to establish project scope and guidelines, as well as providing individual consultancy services to some clients
- ➤ Tools utilized included Adobe CS, Excel, Omniture, Commission Junction, Campaign Monitor, Mailchimp, Rackspace
- * Main platforms used while in this position include Wordpress, Joomla, Zencart

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATION

2007-2010

Bachelor Degree in Computer Science at Canterbury University, UK

Dissertation: "Social networks and their promotions"

2007-2012

Bachelor Degree in Computer Engineering at Universita' di Tor Vergata, Italy

Adobe® Photoshop® CS4 ACE Certified

OTHERS SKILLS AND QUALIFICATION

Excellent IT skills: Microsoft Packages, Open Office, Internet, Outlook, Database Systems including Prestege, Google applications

Masterful in Programming languages: javascript, require.js, angular.js, backbone.js, jquery, json, html, xml, xhtml and css, social networks api.

Masterful in Operation systems: Microsoft Windows, Mac Os x.

Masterful in CMS: Wordpress, Joomla, Joomla (Virtuemart), Opencart, Magento.

Excellent Kwnoledge working: mysql, sql, c++, flash, social media marketing, seo.

Hand coding CSS/HTML: Compatible with IE8, IE* and standards compliant browsers, optimization for portable devices.

Adobe Creative Suite: Expert level. Smart use of colour combination and disposition on websites. Always searching for creative inspirations.

Other work experiences 2004/2010: Computer technician, receptionist at a camp site, sale representative, web producer

Driving: Full Clean Driving Licence (EU) held since 2005

Languages: Italian - native, English- fluent, Spanish - intermediate

SAMPLES

http://www.ukwda.com - UK Web Design Association member
http://www.html.it - I collaborate on an italian online magazine for professional Web designers and developers on voluntary basis

REFERENCES

Available upon request